## **ESTHER WAVINYA NDAVI**

Nairobi, Kenya

+254.742.713.450

estherwavinya80@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a Software Engineer. I am skilled in various Information Technology fields such as Data Analysis, IT Support, IT
Automation, Web development, Software Testing, Digital marketing and Technical Documentation. I am passionate,
energetic and a well organised developer with experience in a variety of engineering fields. I enjoy working in teams and
collaborating in delivering meaningful work.

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- I have the ability for being thorough, deliberate and timely and having attention to detail.
- I do alright in difficult interpersonal situations and at finding ways to effectively resolve disagreements.
- Empathetic, forgiving, supportive, trusting and sensitive to others feelings.
- · Empathy and Sympathy for users/clients.

## INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

- Data Analysis Python
- Software in Test Jira, MS Office, GitHub, Confluence, TestRail, SQL queries, TestLodge, Miro, Charles proxy, Slack
- Digital marketing skills SEO, social media ads, google analytics, email marketing, SEM, WordPress
- UI/UX Design Figma
- Programming languages: JavaScript, Python, VBA, PHP
- Frontend Development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Material CSS, Semantic UI, Ant Design
- Server-Side Development MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, PHP
- IT Support Fundamentals, System administration and Infrastructure Services, Computer Networking, Computer Security

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Andela (Nairobi) JUNE 2021 - Present

TECHNICAL MENTOR - Web Development

- Mentoring and learning support to learners in different teams ie Guiding learners and sharing helpful resources
- · Identifying areas for improvement and Giving learners timely and actionable feedback
- Advising learners on adherence to coding standards, tools and workflows.
- Providing agile product support to dev teams
- Giving tech-related advice to program managers

Technology/Skills: Angular, Google Cloud, Microservices, GitHub, Codacy

# CREATIVE DIGITAL AGENCY(Nairobi)

**OCTOBER 2020 - MARCH 2021** 

# DIGITAL MARKETER & SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER

- Planned and executed all web, SEO/SEM, database marketing, email, social media, and displayed advertising campaigns.
- Designed, built and maintained social media presence.
- Measured and reported performance of all digital marketing campaigns and assessed against goals (ROI and KPIs).
- Tracked and analyzed analytics reports to gain insight on traffic, demographics, and effectiveness; utilized this information to
  positively affect future outcomes
- Collaborated with other departments to manage company reputation, coordinate promotions and increase reach

Technology/Skills: Wordpress, SEO, SEM, Content creating, Google analytics, Social media ads and Email marketing.

## FEMCODE AFRICA (Aba, Nigeria) SOFTWARE ENGINEER

September - December 2020

- I was part of FemHub
- I analyzed users' needs and did designs, tested and developed Software to meet those needs.
- Recommended software upgrades for customers' existing programs and systems.
- Designed each piece of an application/system and planned how the pieces would work together
- Developed frontend website architecture
- Developed backend website applications
- Ensured cross-platform optimization for mobile phones
- Developed servers and databases for functionality
- Ensured responsiveness of applications

Technology/Skills: NodeJS, Microservices, Google cloud, ExpressJS, PHP, SQL Queries

# HNG INTERNSHIP (Lagos, Nigeria) FRONTEND DEVELOPER

May - August 2020

- Responsibilities included translating UI/UX design wireframes to actual code that would produce visual elements of the
  application.
- Developed new user-facing features
- Built reusable code and libraries for future use
- Ensured the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
- Optimized application for maximum speed and scalability
- Ensured that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end
- Collaborated with other team members from different countries

Technology/Skills: Figma, ReactJS, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

# Ministry of Petroleum and Mining (Nairobi, Kenya) GEOLOGIST ATTACHEE

May - August 2019

- Planned geology projects (e.g. oil extraction, water pipe construction) and field sampling events
- Surveyed sites and created logs (e.g. borehole) and maps using GIS (Surveying)
- Gathered and analyzed geological data
- Coordinated research programs
- Examined the composition of samples and specimens using Geochemistry and Mineralogical techniques.
- Measured and tested fossils, rocks, soil, ores and other material with the proper instruments (e.g. X-rays)
- Wrote reports on findings
- · Conducted quality control on the suitability of material (e.g. metals for construction purposes) and inspected projects
- Studied sites for developments, formations, hazards, and composition
- Investigated and evaluated natural resource deposits (e.g. oil)
- Consulted on various geology-related issues like waste management, resource management, gas extraction techniques and more
- Ensured environmental and other regulations were met in construction and production projects (e.g. oil wells)

# **EDUCATION**

Google Africa Developer Scholarship Program (ALC) Mobile Web Development

Kenya, Nairobi county May 2020 - February 2021

University of Nairobi BSc. In Geology/GIS

Kenya, Nairobi county Expected Date of Graduation: Sep, 2021

Mbooni Girls High School Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education Kenya, Makueni county Jan 2013 – Dec 2016

# **EDUCATION** (other)

I have done several online courses in Software Engineering on coursera, udemy, Andela and Google certifications.

- Software in Test Software Testing Masterclass
- Mobile Web Development Mobile Web Development certificate
- IT Support Google IT Support Professional Certificate
- Full Stack development BuildforSDG by Andela
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Fundamentals of Digital Marketing by Google

## **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

#### DigitizeHer Workplace Readiness Program

January 2021 - April 2021

- A mentee in the DigitizeHer Program that focused on soft skills such as Personal Branding, CV and Interview Skills, Imposter Syndrome and its effects, Communications and Corporate Communication skills, Job Search strategies, Thinking Global, Thriving at the workplace, Professional Social Media Presence, Networking and mentorship and Career Development.
- Link to the certificate: DigitizeHer Certificate

# **She Code Africa Mentorship Program**

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020

- A mentee in the She Code Africa mentorship on the web development track for 3 months
- Mainly on the frontend development with JavaScript using ReactJS
- Link to the certificate: She Code Africa

## University of Nairobi, Developer Student Club-core team

Oct 2019 - Present

- Core-team member of DSC leading the web development track in my school and mentor
- Plan workshops for student developers to showcase projects involving communities.
- The link to the community: GDSC UON

# Nairobi University Geology Student Association (NUGSA)

Sep 2017- Present

- A member of NUGSA as a student.
- Its objective is to amplify the voice of students whereas maintaining smooth running with the Department of Geology and school through advocating for student issues, opportunities and events.
- The link to the community: NUGSA

## **REFEREES**

Dr John Waita Sr. Director – Mininstry of Mining +254.722.948.798 Sam Adeniyi Mentor - HNG Internship +234.803.060.0957 mailto:samdeniyi@gmail.com Sharon Jebitok Mentor – She Code Africa +254.702.122.663 mailto:sharonkosgei4@gmail.com